<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Vishvas&#39;s notes</title>
    <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Vishvas&#39;s notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/manufacturing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/manufacturing/</guid>
      <description>Manufacturing Process design: Productivity and quality How to transform the shop-floor/ assembly process and the procurement/ design process to increase quantity and quality?
Quality/ quantity trade-off When the focus is on quantity, quality often suffers, as workers are provided incentives and punishments which, focusing on quantity, largely ignore quality. Quality control is often postponed to a later stage.
The Toyota process, observing that correcting/ tolerating mistakes can be costly, tries to ensure that they get it right the first time - workers have the ability to stop the assembly-line in order to fix a mistake when they make/ detect it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/geo/europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/geo/europe/</guid>
      <description>Europe Economic union Many countries in Europe are part of a union which allows easy travel and relatively free trade with low taxation. Many are also use a common currency, Euro, issued by a central bank.
A big part of the motivation for doing this was to quell fears that the strong German economy might again give rise to an expansionist war-machine.
Euro [Incomplete]
Strength of economies Economic viability of sovereigns is discussed elsewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/geo/japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/geo/japan/</guid>
      <description>Japan Since 1990’s the country has been in ’stagflation’, with the economy shrinking in value due to the government allowing banks to make bad loans without repercussions by bailing them out.
Deficit Faced with a declining work-force, strong anti-immigration sentiment and an aging population, government income is projected to decline compared to its expenditures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/state-level/government/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/state-level/government/</guid>
      <description>Government Services Government agencies or companies hired by them are responsible for providing basic infrastructure - public health-care, roads, water, security, regulation, environment protection, foreign policy, arbitration - to the public.
Design Branches Government has 3 main arms: Legislative (to make laws and oversee policies), Executive (to provide services as designed at a high level by the legislature) and Judiciary (to take care of grievances, punish wrong-doing).
Importance Government design determines the type and the quality of the services provided by the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/state-level/growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/state-level/growth/</guid>
      <description>Economic growth Economic value indicators Certain numbers reveal the current evaluation of the economy. The health of the economy can be roughly viewed in terms of the financial health and confidence of 4 major components: consumers, banks, non-bank businesses, government.
Eg: Prices of critical commodities (like oil), value of index funds, growth in real estate prices, government debt, public debt.
Gross domestic product As a summary This is a measure of the total gross income of the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ads</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/ads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/ads/</guid>
      <description>Fundamentals The basic problem in advertising is finding the audience who is likely to buy the product/ service (target audience).
Placement and position There may be place for a limited number of advertisements to be displayed in a certain venue. Yet, there may be several advertisers competing for those places. Further they may be interested in gaining favorable placement in the ad-list.
Coupon distribution Consider a seller wanting to advertise inventory to target customers, or wanting to spur business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air travel</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/air_travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/air_travel/</guid>
      <description>Factors affecting price Travel date/ day Tickets cost more in certain months.
Tickets tend to cost more on Fridays, saturday, sunday, than on weekdays (especially monday).
Airport demand/ competition Flights from Dallas or houston probably cost less than flights from austin.
Operation costs Some airlines are cheaper than others.
Fuel costs This constitutes a major part of the operating costs.
Airlines which have access to cheaper fuel - either due to a stockpile (Southwest Airlines in 2000-2009), or geographic location (Emirates airlines) can offer lower prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banking</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/banking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/banking/</guid>
      <description>Operation Capital Bank owners make an investment - this is called the capital. A part of the bank’s capital goes towards increasing the size of the capital.
Liabilities/ Borrowed money They also borrow money from investors - in other words, investors deposit money in a bank. The bank promises a return on investment to the depositor, but this return on investment is but a part of the profit the bank makes using that money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bankruptcy</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/fundamentals/bankruptcy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/fundamentals/bankruptcy/</guid>
      <description>Definition When a company declares bankruptcy, it says that it is incapable of meeting all of its financial commitments/ liabilities. All of its agreements with trade-unions are then also canceled.
The business’s assets can be liquidated (seized, valued and sold) to satisfy its liabilities. Also, the company may be taken over and restructured; and the new owner can repay outstanding debts.
Rescue Motivation The government is often motivated to rescue failing businesses to prevent negative consequences like job loss, reduction in national pride etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charts</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/trading/charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/trading/charts/</guid>
      <description>These are especially useful for highly liquid items Eg: negotiable securities. Portfolio decisions can be based on looking at the chart for the appropriate time period. With a chart, one can observe features like support and resistence levels. Thence, one can decide whether it is a good time to buy or sell an equity.
This is because charts contain in them the evaluations of large fund managers etc.. But that can be misleading in case of bubbles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/geo/china/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/geo/china/</guid>
      <description>Chinese economy is growing at a fast pace. Politically, China seems to be stable in the short to medium term.
Manufacturing China has a trade surplus relative to the USA. It is a manufacturing hub.
Media China, due to tight censorship, does not seem to be a hot-spot for internet businesses. It blocks Facebook, twitter - anything which can be used to organize subversion of the government.
Middle class 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distribution</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/distribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/distribution/</guid>
      <description>Retail vs wholesale Retail business focuses on distributing goods to consumers, while making a profit. Wholesalers focus on selling goods in bulk at a lower price to other businesses and distributors. Eg in USA: Sam’s club, costco. In India: Metro.
Price discrimination Different people are willing to pay different prices for the same product, and retailers try to exploit this.
In general, retailers try to distinguish the two types of customers by offering lower prices only to those who participate in some undesirable process which costs extra time and attention- eg: waiting for a certain day to make a purchase, committing to purchase in advance, gathering coupons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food making</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/food/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/food/</guid>
      <description>Agriculture Resources Agriculture requires non-saline water, fertile land, seeds, labor. Of these, overall, water is often most scarce.
Artificial production Research is on to produce meat in-vitro.
Demand and supply Past The discovery of agriculture enabled mass, reliable food production. For most of history, we have had a food surplus. When there was a famine in one country, one could rely on imports from another.
Forecast Human population is growing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funds</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/funds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/funds/</guid>
      <description>Relying on experts or algorithms One can mitigate risks by relying on experts or well-tested algorithms to manage funds. In USA, publicly traded companies which follow the value investing philosophy include: Berkshire Hathaway, BBTEX, Boyar, Tweedy Borwne, YACKX.
Index funds for a given economic sector simply invest in major companies in proportion to their market value. One relys on the less riskier supposition that the entire sector is likely to grow, rather than any single security belonging to that sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Futures</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/trading/futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/trading/futures/</guid>
      <description>Anticipated trade One agent makes a deal with another to buy a certain amount of an ’underlying’ security on a specified future date at a certain ’strike’ price. To satisfy this deal, the seller is obliged to buy the security - if he does not already hold it - on or before the due-date.
Motivation The seller is betting that the market price of the security on or before the due-date will be lower than the set price; and the buyer is betting that the market price will exceed the set-price on or after the due-date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gambling</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/gambling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/gambling/</guid>
      <description>Bet contract 2 outcomes Consider an event E. A bet between two people (A and B) is a contract which says that if E comes to pass (usually by a specified time), person A will pay an amount x to B; otherwise if E doesn’t happen, B will pay y to A.
y is called the bet liability.
Viability of the bet Rational B (who is not risk-averse) will enter the contract if according to his evaluation of a, _a__x_ − (1 − a)_y_ ≥ 0 or $a \geq \frac{y}{x+y}$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goal setting</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/goal/</guid>
      <description>Importance of planning An individual earns money from employment when young and healthy; but eventually they retire or get sick- either early or after going old.
Many expenses are very predictable. Hence set up a retirement fund, children’s education fund, health/ emergency fund. Many people fail at doing this.
Goals Investment horizon and age One should be clear about the investment horizon: when does one intend to withdraw money from the fund, with what frequency etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goods and services</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/goods/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/goods/intro/</guid>
      <description>Public goods Traits Non-exclusion Once the good has been provided - possibly with the support of certain people, there is no good way of excluding others (including unconnected ’free-riders’) from using it.
Non-rivalry Use of the good by a person does not make it less enjoyable or worthwhile for other users.
Examples Fresh air, pleasant weather. More controversial examples: roads.
Funding Provision of public goods is often done by the government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/implementation/</guid>
      <description>Execution Summary समीकरणम् (rebalancing)  करवृद्धिरहित-लेखासु यथेष्टम् काले काले करव्याप्तौ स्थितासु लेखासु वर्षे वर्षे। कराधिक्यम् वारयितुम्।  अमेरिकेषु  TD Ameritrade इत्यत्र my account -&amp;gt; portfolio planner प्रयोगः पूर्वतटव्यवहारसमये। Use total money to be invested.  भारतेषु Post tax  Look up symbols in BSE and NSE websites. Sometimes equity is listed in both - only &amp;ldquo;EQ&amp;rdquo; is added in symbols to differentiate. upstox order tips: https://www.evernote.com/notelink/Login.action?targetUrl=%2Fshard%2Fs440%2Fnl%2F75394722%2Ff9a8ba31-ac3a-4c70-a836-4ead7b16439b%2F  Tax saving  Explore funds on morning-star : see 5 yr returns, expense ratio https://upstox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual spending</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/spending/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/spending/</guid>
      <description>Conspicuous consumption This is done mainly for the purpose of increasing one’s status in society (aka ’status signaling’). This is aka ’keeping up with the joneses’.
Green consumption People might want to similarly enhance status among environmentally conscious people by making conspicuous green choices - even though a less conspicuous investment may have benefited the ecosystem more. Eg: Installing solar panels on street side of the house, Buying the distinctive Toyota Prius rather than other inconspicuous hybrid vehicles around 2010’s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insurance</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/insurance/</guid>
      <description>Insurance products, besides serving the main purpose of hedging to counter financial risk, often also function as investment in mutual funds.
Functioning As security This business takes advantage of the fact that risk of a particular kind (house burning down, theft, death), affects a small fraction of a population at any given time, with very high probability. So, it collects fees/ premiums from a large number of insured people, and compensates those on whom a bad event befalls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermediary trading</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/intermediary_trading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/intermediary_trading/</guid>
      <description>Basic negotiable securities tradings actions are considered elsewhere.
Role in markets Intermediary traders buy and sell items, holding them for a short time while it changes hands between long-term investors. In doing so, they make a profit.
So, they focus strongly on the guessing and taking advantage of the motives of investors - aka front-running investors.
Liquidity, cost The benefit they provide is in bringing greater liquidity to assets, buy supplying a sea of ready purchasing and selling power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/fundamentals/0_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/fundamentals/0_intro/</guid>
      <description>Organizations Mission Some organizations are focused on earning money for their owners by pursuing and growing a certain business.
Charitable organizations are focused on gathering resources (usually from donations) and spending them to promote social good by a ceratin type of activity. They are usually managed by a board of trustees.
Ownership At any given point in time, it is clear from documentation/ declaration who the owners of a business are, what portion of the business they own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/intro/</guid>
      <description>Core idea Investment involves financing/ owning businesses - perhaps by buying stocks or bonds, with the aim of getting a good return on investment and with little risk of loss.
Future Discount factor For most people and organizations, _x_ amount of money today is better than _k__x_ amount of money one year from now, where _k_ &amp;gt; 1. One reason for this is inflation.
Among individuals Discount factor is much steeper in the short-term than in the long term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Labor</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/fundamentals/labor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/fundamentals/labor/</guid>
      <description>Hiring in businesses Academic hiring follows a different pattern.
Selectivity Hiring people is generally easier than getting rid of them. So, when possible, businesses create interview processes which have low ’false positive’ rates - even at the cost of high ’false negative’ rates.
Process Often, specialized recruiters are used to make initial contacts with people - in order to get an idea of where how the candidate may fit the company’s needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misc</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/misc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/misc/</guid>
      <description>Arbitrage Goods/ services often have different values in different markets. So, often people can fulfill demand in the market where an item is costlier by buying it from a market where it is cheaper and getting it to the costlier market.
For securities traded in different stock exchanges, automatons do this effectively.
Crime This is considered in the ’society’ survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/state-level/money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/state-level/money/</guid>
      <description>Money and value The value of goods and services, for various people, keeps changing in accordance with demand and supply for it. Money is a common way of expressing this value numerically.
Value of money, goods If more value has been created in the economy, if no new money is created/ the amount of money in the system remains the same, then the value of money increases, and there is deflation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Options</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/trading/options/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/trading/options/</guid>
      <description>Definition The buyer of an option gains the right (not obligation) to buy or sell (depending on the option type) an underlying security (100 shares in case of a standard option) at a specified strike price per share by a certain expiration day in case of American-style options (which we consider here), or exactly on a certain day in case of European-style options.
The seller of such an option is called a writer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orders</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/trading/trading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/trading/trading/</guid>
      <description>Here we consider basic (possibly multi-step) actions involving various negotiable instruments in the market.
Buying and selling Basic actions in a stock market are to buy or sell a security. The securities exchange has programs/ machines which effectively communicate the price of various stocks based on what prices people are asking/ willing to pay for them - by recording these bids.
Market price order A market order is an order to buy or sell a stock at the current market price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Payment</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/payment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/businesses/payment/</guid>
      <description>Credit cards Credit cards are a relatively safe way for lenders to encourage public borrowing while making purchases - that way, they can make a profit.
Stores - possibly getting a commission - often offer credit cards (with attractive terms) under their brand-name to their customers; but they are actually managed by banks.
The necessary infrastructure is managed by one of a handful of companies - like Visa, MasterCard, AmericanExpress etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>Summary Also see implementation summary.
 Pick a simple asset allocation model, stick to it, rebalance occasionally.  Possibly put a small portion of money in high-risk high-reward places. (NN Taleb&amp;rsquo;s barbell strategy.)  Initially, be equity heavy. But put some money in bonds (negatively correlated with equity).  USA - TSM core 5&amp;frasl;8, SV tilt 3&amp;frasl;8.  Switch to fixed income heavy portfolio when retiring.  &amp;ldquo;Let us call the first set ensemble probability (concerned with a collection of people) and the second one time probability or ergodicity (concerned with one person through time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/risk/</guid>
      <description>Risk and return-advantage types Risk in the investment is the potential to loose money. Risk is paired with advantage: investors promised a bigger return will tolerate some risk.
Credit default risk This risk is particularly relevant for bonds. This is the risk of businesses not repaying their loans.
The advantage is that riskier bonds yield bigger returns.
Credit rating agencies Sometimes, the ultimate owners of bonds sometimes do not have a clear idea about the risk involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tradeables</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/goods/tradeables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/goods/tradeables/</guid>
      <description>Negotiable instruments Aka Securities. These are objects which promise payment to whoever holds the object. They include: stocks/ equities (which represent ownership in various businesses/ funds), bonds (loans), derivatives (whose value is determined based on the value of other instruments).
Creating securities Investment bankers help raise capital for various businesses by creating bonds and stocks. They get big fees for it.
Underwriting They often take the responsibility of selling such securities by purchasing it from the business and holding on to them - usually until they can sell it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USA</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/geo/usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/geo/usa/</guid>
      <description>General economy USA has high trade deficit: especially with oil producing countries and manufacturers like China.
GDP Growth is much lower than in emerging economies: 0-3%.
Industry USA’s industry is highly innovative - one of the best in the world. Industries are highly mechanized.
Manufacturing America is the biggest manufacturer of goods in the world. But, much of the manufacturing is done in highly automated factories which are run by a handful of skilled employees overseeing the automation; manufacturing involving low skilled labour has moved to countries (in the developing world) with cheaper labor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valuation</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/valuation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/investing/valuation/</guid>
      <description>Beliefs and market positions Agents, in trading securities, bet on change in market’s evaluation of securities. Thus, the market price of securities is adjusted continually.
If agents believe that a security will increase in value, they are said to act from a bullish/ long position. If the reverse is true, they are said to act from a bearish/ short position.
Agents may also believe a certain company will outperform or underperform other companies in the sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/trading/infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vvasuki.github.io/notes/artha/economics/trading/infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>Securities Exchanges Stock markets provide a regulated/ facilitated environment for carrying out securities transactions/ trades. It operates in fixed trading hours - beyond those hours, brokers may trade on their amongst themselves in extended trading hours.
Brokerages Every trade is accomplished by agents/ brokers authorized to trade in the stock market - usually on behalf of their customers. A fraction of each trade is usually collected by the stock exchange as fees.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>